Guide to the William Minter Papers, 1960-2016 RL.11769
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William Minter papers
1960-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Minter, William, 1942-
John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
RL.11769
17.1 Linear Feet
William Minter is a free-lance writer, researcher, and consultant primarily on Africa-related issues, based in Washington, DC. Collection comprises Minter's personal cilippings files on general health issues in Africa, foreign relations, as well as AIDS and ebola. Among the sources for the clippings are the Washington Post, New York Times, as well as websites and listservs for each topic.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Health, AIDS, Ebola, and Foreign Relations.
Biographical / Historical
William Minter is a free-lance writer, researcher, and consultant primarily on Africa-related issues, based in Washington, DC. Beginning in 1995, he founded an on-line publication distributed by e-mail and on-the-web for the Washington Office on Africa and its affiliate Washington Office on Africa Educational Fund (later Africa Policy Information Center). In 2003 that publication became an independent project under the name of AfricaFocus Bulletin. A full archive is available on-line at http://www.africafocus.org.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The William Minter Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018 and 2021.
Related Materials
The LeRoy T. Walker Africa News Service Archive.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises Minter's personal clippings files on general health issues in Africa, Foreign Relations, as well as AIDS and ebola. Among the sources for the cilppings are the Washington Post, New York Times, as well as websites and listservs for each topic.
Health in mass media -- Africa; Ebola virus disease; AIDS (Disease); Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome; Clippings files; Clippings (information artifacts); Africa -- Foreign relations; Minter, William, 1942-; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
- Health, 1987-2016
  Scope and Contents
  Clippings files for various general health topics, including AIDS, ebola, cholera, maleria, tuberculosis, polio, female genital mutilation, drug prices and access to medicine, birth control, childbirth, vaccine experiments, health strategies, traditional medicine, and regional approaches to treatment.
  - Clippings, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1993-1995 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2002-2003; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2004; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2011-2012; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2013 (Box 1)
  - Jan-June, 2014 (Box 1)
  - July-Dec, 2014 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2015 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 2016 (Box 1)
- AIDS, 1996-2008
  Clippings files on various topics, including regional responses to the crisis and access to treatment, global approaches to treatment and funding, orphans, drug costs, F.P.A. (Foreign Policy Association) responses, transmission, and blood safety.
  - Science/origin, 1996-2001 (Box 2)
  - AIDS study session, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Botswana, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - South Africa, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - US, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - FPA Africa overview, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - Treatment, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - Jan-Mar, 2001; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Apr-May, 2001 (Box 2)
  - June-July, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Aug-Dec, 2001; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Uganda, 2001 (Box 2)
  - FPA, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Senegal, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Overview, 2001-2002 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, 2002; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - FPA Key Articles, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Jan-June, 2003; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - July-Sept, 2003; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Oct-Dec, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Jan-Mar, 2004; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Apr-June, 2004 (Box 3)
  - July-Dec, 2004; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Jan-June, 2005 (Box 3)
  - July-Dec, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Safe Medical Care, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 2007-2008; 2 folders (Box 3)
- Ebola, 2014-2015
  Clippings files regarding Ebola outbreaks in Liberia and Sierra Leone as well as other West African countries, and global responses. Other topics include vaccines, funding, quarantines, and testing.
  - September, 2014 (Box 4)
  - October, 2014; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Nov-Dec, 2014; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Clippings, 2015; 2 folders (Box 5)
- Foreign Relations, 1960-2013
  Includes clippings files related to foreign relations in Africa and Southern Africa. There are files relating to specific countries such as South Africa, Zaire, and Angola. This series is unprocessed and the box list was made from an inventory.
  - U.S. Foreign Relations South Africa: Economics, 1992 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Foreign Relations Southern Africa, 1960-1983 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Foreign Relations South Africa, 1969-1986 (Box 7)
  - U.S. Foreign Relations South Africa, 1987-1998 (Box 8)
  - U.S. Foreign Relations Africa, 1985-1994 (Box 9)
  - U.S. Foreign Relations Angola, 1991 (Box 10)
  - U.S. Foreign Relations Zaire, 1992 (Box 10)
  - U.S. Foreign Relations Africa, 1995-1999 (Box 11)
  - U.S. Foreign Relations Africa, 1998-2004 (Box 12)
  - U.S. Foreign Relations and U.S. Foreign Relations Africa, 2004-2013 (Box 13)